<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sarath blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sarath blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:14:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Before AI, There Was Discipline</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/before-ai-there-was-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:14:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/before-ai-there-was-discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-ai-there-was-discipline&#34;&gt;Before AI, There Was Discipline&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this now for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My father has just received the DGP’s Commendation Disc – Silver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most people will scroll past that line.&#xA;Awards are common.&#xA;Respect is not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But that medal forced me to think about something deeper —&#xA;why people like him still exist, and why fewer people can survive that life today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is not a tribute.&#xA;It is an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo static website builder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-fifth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-fifth-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-hugo&#34;&gt;What is Hugo?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a fast and flexible static site generator. It’s written in Go and allows you to build a website that can be deployed anywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly fast, easy to use, and helps you create static websites that can be hosted on platforms like Netlify, GitHub Pages, or any server capable of serving static content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-use-hugo&#34;&gt;Why Use Hugo?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed&lt;/strong&gt;: Hugo is designed for speed, meaning even large websites can be built in a matter of seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;: It has a wide range of themes and customization options.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Posts and content are written in Markdown, making them easy to manage and format.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-hugo&#34;&gt;Setting Up Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install Hugo: You can install Hugo on your local machine from the official website.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a New Site: Run the &lt;code&gt;hugo new site &amp;lt;sitename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; command to create a new Hugo site.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add a Theme: Choose a theme from the Hugo themes website and add it to your site.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create Content: Write your posts in Markdown and define metadata in the front matter like I’ve shown above.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hugo makes creating static websites simple, fast, and flexible. Whether you’re building a personal blog or a more complex website, Hugo offers a great solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Vs Typescript</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;javascript-vs-typescript-understanding-the-differences&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript vs TypeScript: Understanding the Differences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When building web applications, the debate between &lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;TypeScript&lt;/strong&gt; is one that often comes up. Both are essential tools in the world of web development, but they serve different purposes and have distinct characteristics. Understanding these differences can help developers choose the best language for their project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-javascript&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is JavaScript?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt; is the most widely used scripting language for web development. It allows developers to add interactive elements to websites, from form validation to animations and more. JavaScript is &lt;strong&gt;dynamically typed&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that types are assigned during runtime, which offers flexibility but can also lead to runtime errors if not properly managed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MERN Stack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;mern-stack-a-full-stack-javascript-solution-for-modern-web-development&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MERN Stack: A Full-Stack JavaScript Solution for Modern Web Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;MERN&lt;/strong&gt; stack is a popular collection of technologies that allows developers to build powerful, full-stack web applications entirely in JavaScript. It combines &lt;strong&gt;MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Express.js&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;React.js&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Node.js&lt;/strong&gt;, each contributing a vital role in the development process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;: A flexible, scalable NoSQL database that stores data in JSON-like format, making it ideal for handling unstructured data and large datasets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Express.js&lt;/strong&gt;: A minimalist web framework for Node.js that simplifies backend development by providing essential tools for routing, middleware, and API handling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;React.js&lt;/strong&gt;: A JavaScript library for building dynamic, user-friendly interfaces. React uses components to create interactive UIs, making it easier to manage state and render updates efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node.js&lt;/strong&gt;: A JavaScript runtime built on Chrome&amp;rsquo;s V8 engine, enabling server-side programming with JavaScript. It’s known for its high performance and scalability, making it perfect for real-time applications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The MERN stack is highly favored for building single-page applications (SPAs), real-time applications, and dynamic websites. By using JavaScript across both the front-end and back-end, developers can streamline their development process, improve efficiency, and maintain a consistent codebase.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>React</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-reactjs&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is React.js?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;React.js&lt;/strong&gt; is a popular open-source JavaScript library used for building dynamic, high-performance user interfaces, particularly for single-page applications (SPAs). Developed and maintained by Facebook, React simplifies the process of building complex UIs by breaking them into smaller, reusable components.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;key-features-of-react&#34;&gt;Key Features of React:&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Component-Based Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; React’s component-based structure allows developers to build applications by composing small, independent, and reusable components.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual DOM:&lt;/strong&gt; React uses a virtual DOM, which allows for efficient rendering by updating only the parts of the actual DOM that need to change. This makes React fast and responsive, even with large applications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Way Data Binding:&lt;/strong&gt; React follows a unidirectional data flow, which simplifies debugging and improves the predictability of application behavior.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JSX Syntax:&lt;/strong&gt; React uses JSX (JavaScript XML), a syntax extension that allows HTML to be written within JavaScript code, making the UI more readable and intuitive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;React is widely used for building scalable, maintainable, and interactive UIs. Its flexibility and performance make it a great choice for developing both simple and complex web applications. Whether you’re building a personal blog or an enterprise-level app, React.js provides the tools to create an excellent user experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zustand: The Easiest Way for State Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-fourth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-fourth-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;State management is a critical aspect of modern web development, especially for React applications. While libraries like Redux are powerful, they can often feel overly complex for smaller or medium-sized projects. Enter &lt;strong&gt;Zustand&lt;/strong&gt;—a minimalist and efficient library for state management that simplifies the process without compromising flexibility or performance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-zustand&#34;&gt;What is Zustand?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zustand&lt;/strong&gt; (German for &amp;ldquo;state&amp;rdquo;) is a lightweight state management library for React. Created by the developers of Jotai and React-spring, it offers an intuitive API and eliminates boilerplate, making it a breeze to manage application state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
